hey everyone welcome again to another
lesson in the stores car automation
course today I am going to show you how
you can use repetitions in Tosca to run
your test steps repeatedly and number of
times I am going to show you two ways of
doing this in your Tosca automation test
cases
for this purpose I have created a new
folder and I have created a test case
flow in which we'll be using repetitions
so we'll be using the same app what I'll
be doing is I'll be
going to this URL I'll be using this
username and password to login
and then what I'm going to do
just let me get clear of this
notifications and then what I will do is
I'm going to click on this add to cart
button
five times now this might not be an
ideal scenario where you will use
repetitions but if you want to also do
some performance testing on your
elements
or on your application you can also use
this repetitions or else if you have a
specific scenario where we want to
repeat your test steps
so you can use this repetitions logic
which I'm going to show you
okay so let me reset this app State and
let's log out
and let's close this okay so as I told
you I'm going I have added these steps
where I'm going to login First into the
application and then I've got this
repetition test step right or a
repetition test case inside this I have
a test step for adding products as I
showed you
and the reputation would be
in this particular folder okay so the
steps inside this folder will be
repeated again and again and that is to
click on the add to cart button okay as
I showed you and then we are going to
close the application
okay so let's see how we can add these
repetitions to our test steps so uh for
our case the test step is to add the
products multiple times okay or click on
the add to cart button multiple times
so as I said earlier there are two ways
of doing this okay
so the first way is to add another extra
column in your test cases section where
you can add repetitions
and how you can do that is go to this
particular section and right click here
and you will see there is an option
called column Chooser okay so this way
uh you can add any number of columns or
different columns to your test cases
so here you will find there is a column
called repetition now either you can
drag and drop this into uh your sections
column section or you can also double
click it to just add it to your columns
okay and it will currently show it under
The Columns of your test cases
once you do that you have got the
repetition column and now you can add
any number of repetitions here
um
which you want to run this test steps
okay so this will not be at uh the test
step level you cannot add it here or you
cannot add it under the test case you
have to add it in the folder under which
your test steps are there okay so if you
want to run all of these steps under
this folder
um multiple number of times then you
have to mention it here so for example
if I do five times okay I want to run
this five times I have added a
repetition of five
okay so that's all I need to do and
let's go ahead and see whether this is
working or not okay
so I'm going to run this particular
folder which contains all the steps
and as you can see now it is logging in
and it is trying to click on the add to
cart multiple times okay
just ignore that notification on the
Chrome browser it is giving on some
password being used uh maliciously
so if we ignore that particular thing
and we go to the results of the scratch
book you will see in add products folder
we have got five repetitions so let me
expand this
and you will see it has got this step
which has been executed multiple times
or the number of times we decided okay
so this way you can add repetitions to
your test steps which will be repeated
multiple number of times okay
now this was just the one way of doing
it okay uh now let's look at another way
of doing this so let me remove this
okay you can also remove uh your columns
uh if I haven't mentioned it earlier you
can just drag your column and that is a
cross sign on your screen so just leave
it and your column would be removed okay
so now um I have removed the repetition
uh column value here from the add
products folder so it's not going to run
any repetition for my test steps but I'm
going to show you the other way okay so
go to the properties section and here
you will also find a property called
repetition okay only for this particular
folder so
here I can again mention uh to run this
repetitions rather four times this time
okay so let's try a different number
so this is now set to run the repetition
uh for the test steps under this folder
for four times okay and it is set in the
properties section not in the column
section okay
uh but as you can see once I set it in
the properties section the column
section is automatically updated okay
so it's one and the same thing but uh
there are two ways of doing it okay
so now if I go ahead and run
so running this again in scratchbook and
now it should basically do the same
thing
okay so it is going to click on the add
to cart multiple times
and we can see the same thing uh in our
results
so let's expand this result section
and go to the add products and you can
see four repetitions okay so last time
around we had five repetitions and now
we have four
so this is how you can um add
repetitions to your test steps so that
they are executed multiple number of
times that depends as I said uh on your
scenario of the application you are
testing
although uh the scenario I showed was
not the perfect example but at least uh
now you got an idea on how you can use
repetitions in your Tosca test cases
and before we end this topic let me show
you another small thing which is quite
noticeable or not noticeable so when we
add some repetition to a folder the
folder icon changes okay so you can see
a rounded Arrow going backwards uh
Whenever there is a repetition
and if I remove this repetition now you
will see the folder has again changed to
a normal folder okay so that's the sign
you need to look for if there is any
repetition for any particular test steps
which are part of that folder okay
so this is all about repetitions uh look
out for more videos
um coming up soon
um in Tosca again